Elrey C. Belmonti

Junior Developer

Personal Info

Phone

267.325.2985

E-mail

elbelmonti@gmail.com

GitHub

https://github.com/ElreyB

LinkedIn

https://www.linkedin.com/in/elreyb/

Technology is no longer only for computer science majors and mathematicians but our everyday life. Being a passionate people-person with over 10 years of experience as a professional dancer and in the hospitality industry; bringing tech and communities together is a dedication of mines. After a year and a half sabbatical, wire jewelry making and briefly attending Dev Bootcamp, I attended and graduated from Epicodus. There I spent six months coding over 1000 hours and built web applications from scratch. Now, after finishing my internship I am enthusiastic to bring my development skills to your team/company.

Education

2017-08 -

Epicodus

2018-02

- lead by example/influence and deliver ideas compellingly
- singled-handedly built a web application that helps dancers find jobs in Seattle and engage in the dance community
- created an interactive learning tool that allows children the ability to create a personalized approach to learning
- · initiated a communication tool that streamlined information sharing and event planning for the class

2016-09 -

Dev Bootcamp

2017-05

- Increased my knowledge in Practical Object Oriented Design in Ruby and algorithms
- Coached relieving stress techniques to peers
- Actively participated in Engineer Empathy lectures

Projects

Epic-Goose (Group Project); HTML, CSS, Javascript, Bootstrap

Conceptualized and served as team lead on a choose your own journey story application following the story of "Goblin Market".

Live site: https://elreyb.github.io/epic-goose/, Github: https://github.com/ElreyB/epic-goose

Triangle Tracker; Ruby Rspec, Sinatra, Heroku, Pry, Capybara, JavaScript

A personal interactive dictionary for kids making learning fun. Live Site: https://glacial-meadow-45856.herokuapp.com/, Glthub:https://github.com/ElreyB/word-definer

Triangle Tracker; HTML, CSS, jQuery, Bootstrap

An application that will determine if the three numbers inputed will make a triangle and what basic type of triangle it is. Live Site: https://elreyb.github.io/triangle-tracker/,

Github: https://github.com/ElreyB/triangle-tracker

Experience

2018-01 -

Intern

2018-02

ChalkDoc

- Identify and addressed tech debt
- Organized daily goals
- Refactored existing code base using higher order functions & reduced total source lines of code by 60%
- Ensured consistent and thorough documentation

2005-09 -

Manager, Host, Event Planner

2015-11

Hospitality Industry

- Full cycled event planning for parties up to 100 people
- · Comfortable working with high-end clienteles, including celebrities and corporations
- · Solidified relationships with repeat clients to deliver their party vision to reality
- · Single-handedly created host manuals and trainings for four [high end] restaurants

2002-04 -

Dancer, Choreographer

2015-10

Dance Companies In Philadelphia and Seattle Area

- Established a large network in the dance community
- Participated in several dance companies that exchanged dance concepts with international companies
- Lead classes in modern dance and yoga for local communities